An Inventory of the Richard B. Foster papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Richard B. Foster papers
1955-1999
2004C41
Foster, Richard B.
Hoover Institution Archives
87 manuscript boxes (34.8 linear feet)
The Richard B. Foster papers document the work of a leading American national security analyst in the Cold War period. In a career spanning three decades, Foster specialized in strategic forecasting, attempting to predict future military and political developments on the basis of existing trends. He conducted research and wrote about many aspects of American defense policy, especially in relation to the possibility of nuclear war between the United States and the Soviet Union. As the director of the Strategic Studies Center at SRI International (formerly Stanford Research Institute), Foster wrote or collaborated on numerous reports that addressed a wide range of national security issues, including military strategy, ballistic missile defense, arms control, and telecommunications. These reports comprise the largest part of the Foster collection. In addition, the collection contains a number of articles Foster wrote for various journals, as well as drafts of his unpublished study of the history of American strategic doctrine.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Biography
1916 Born, Springfield, Washington
1938 Awarded bachelor's degree, University of California at Berkeley
1954 Joined Stanford Research Institute (later SRI International) as manager of Air Defense Evaluation Program
1965-1984 Director, Strategic Studies Center, SRI International
1978 Founding editor, Comparative Strategy
1980s Taught courses on strategy at Georgetown University and Catholic University of America
1999 Died
Arrangement Statement
Materials that are listed under the same headings in the finding aid are sometimes located in more than one range of boxes within the collection. Stanford Research Institute and SRI International reports are found in boxes 1-39 and boxes 64-79. Speeches and writings are in boxes 40-54 and boxes 80-82. Printed matter is located in boxes 60-64 and boxes 84-86.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Richard B. Foster papers document the work of a leading American national security analyst in the Cold War period. In a career spanning three decades, Foster specialized in strategic forecasting, attempting to predict future military and political developments on the basis of existing trends. He conducted research and wrote about many aspects of American defense policy, especially in relation to the possibility of nuclear war between the United States and the Soviet Union. As the director of the Strategic Studies Center at SRI International (formerly Stanford Research Institute), Foster wrote or collaborated on numerous reports that addressed a wide range of national security issues, including military strategy, ballistic missile defense, arms control, and telecommunications. These reports comprise the largest part of the Foster collection. In addition, the collection contains a number of articles Foster wrote for various journals, as well as drafts of his unpublished study of the history of American strategic doctrine.
The SRI reports dealing with nuclear warfare include speculation as to how such a conflict might unfold, presenting various scenarios of destruction and possible recovery from a nuclear exchange. Other reports in the collection focus on the military power of the Soviet Union and what Foster and other SRI analysts perceived to be Soviet attempts to achieve strategic superiority vis-a-vis the United States. There are also analyses of various issues pertaining to American diplomacy, including relations with China and Europe. These include a number of studies authored by Foster that assess the implications of changes in American foreign policy during the Nixon administration.
The collection also contains copies of lectures given by Foster at Georgetown University and the Catholic University of America, as well as some correspondence and memoranda pertaining to Foster's work at SRI International. There are also materials relating to Foster's service on the board of directors of Freedom House, including reports on various human rights issues. The printed matter in the collection is largely concerned with military policy and diplomatic history.
SRI International.; Arms control.; Ballistic missile defenses.; Nuclear weapons.; Strategy.; Telecommunication.
- Stanford Research Institute and SRI International reports, 1959-1987
  - Telecommunications policy, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 1: 1-6)
  - Prolonged conflict, 1981 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Prolonged war and nuclear targeting, 1980 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Telecommunications policy, 1981 (Box-folder 2: 1-4)
  - Alternative radiological systems, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Debris distribution, 1981 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Complilation of Soviet views on MBFR (Mutual Balanced Force Reductions), 1973 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Implications of Indian and/or Japanese nuclear proliferation, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Utility of nuclear weapons employment in peripheral conflicts, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Soviet responses, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 10-11)
  - Selected economic and foreign aid data, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Problems regarding nuclear proliferation, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Soviet military policy, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 14-15)
  - Potential economic capacity, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Preliminary description of USSR expenditures, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Political views on the burden of defense, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Research by SRI/SSC (Stanford Research Institute/Strategic Studies Center)for DDR&E (Director of Defense Reserach and Engineering), 1973 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Relationships between changes in ruble/dollar conversion ratios, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Final report: research by SRI/SSC for DDR&E, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - The use of barter to procure military supplies, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - A survey of the literature on limited strategic war, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Potential economic issues, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Emergent international system, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Citizen-army concept in Germany, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Dynamics of evolving from a strategy of mutually assured destruction, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Role of military force, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - European economic integration, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Strategic rationale for the defense of the NCA (National Command Authority), 1974 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Integrated global force posture analysis, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - United States security interests in Pacific-Asia, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Lessons from the Vietnamese War, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Observations on determinants of Soviet strategy, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Latin America, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Food supply and production, 1958 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Manufacturing facility requirements, 1960 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Bibliography of defense research, 1973 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - U.S. Department of Defense formulation of research, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - U.S. telecommunications in the 1980s, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 9-10)
  - Brief analysis of national security and emergency preparedness, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Emerging impact of foreign competition, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Origin of the AT&T national defense policy, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Leadtime reduction with quick reaction facilities, 1959 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Summary of discussion at the SSC colloquium, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - U.S. security interests in the Middle East-Indian Ocean area, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Decisionmaking in the USSR, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Soviet military capabilities, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Soviet military posture, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Soviet policy and the Arab-Israeli conflict of 1974 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Soviet oil problems, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Elements of Western economic dependence on the USSR, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Soviet Union and Egyptian-Syrian preparations for the Arab-Israeli War of 1973, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Soviet economic dependence on Western Europe, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Soviet policy towards Western Europe, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Detente and Soviet policy in Europe, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Oil and Soviet foreign policy, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Summary volume: Soviet strategy and foreign policy, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Role of social science research institutes, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - East-West trade and postwar Soviet economic growth, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - West German defense predilections, 1973 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Specifications and properties of an econometric model of the Soviet Union, 1974 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Economic aspects of daily life in the USSR, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - An exercise in scenario analysis with the SRI-WEFA (Stanford Research Institute-Wharton Econometric Forecasting Associates)model, 1974 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Notes on the economics of detente, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Observations on long-term economic developments in the USSR, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Strategic forecast: U.S. Navy beyond the year 2000, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - The SRI-WEFA Soviet econometric model, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Great power interests and conflicting objectives, 1974 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Assessment of alternative long-range Soviet growth strategies, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Effects of nuclear attacks on the petroleum industry, 1960 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Consequences of the 1975 Soviet harvest (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Analytical framework for assessing combat service support, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Arms, oil, and strategy, 1974 (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
  - Background studies: Great power interests, 1974 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - U.S. strategy in the event of a failure of detente, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 5-6)
  - Maintenance of U.S. forces in Korea, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 7-8)
  - Expanded U.S.-Japanese security for the 1980s, 1981 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Redressing the strategic nuclear imbalance in Northeast Asia, 1982 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - A strategic framework of arms control verification, 1982 (Box-folder 8: 3-4)
  - Soviet opportunities in the Third World, 1976 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Observations on American-Soviet trade, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Living in the shadow of Moscow, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Detente: Western and Soviet interpretations, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Some Soviet vulnerabilities, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Selected aspects of the Soviet civil defense program, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Soviet high command, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - A survey of Soviet general and flag officers, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Factors motivating Soviet strategic weapons development, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Near-nuclear countries and nonproliferation, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Study of possible Soviet strategy of controlled conflict, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 1-4)
  - Issues and alternative organization and management structures, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Transfer of U.S. technology to the Soviet Union, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 6-7)
  - Soviet imports of technology, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Mineral dependence in Western Europe, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Development of prototype crisis relocation plans, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - A system of centers for research into counter-guerrilla operations, 1961 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - West European perceptions of NATO, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
  - Soviet perceptions of the United States, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 3-4)
  - West European NATO policies and trends, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - NATO standardization concepts, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Detente: a balance sheet, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - NATO cooperation, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 8-9)
  - U.S. Air Force role in NATO standardization, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 10-11)
  - Reflections on detente, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - Issue of forward based systems, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Biological availability and uptake of fission products, 1962 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Preliminary evaluation of fire hazards from nuclear detonations, 1962 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Preliminary appraisal of NS/EP (National Security/Emergency Preparedness), 1982 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - National security trends and AT&T alternatives, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
  - The law of war, 1962 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Optical communications systems, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - System of financing research and development, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Financing research and development, 1981 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Training and utilization of scientific and engineering-technical personnel, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
  - Training and utilization of scientists and engineers, 1981 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Feasibility of crisis relocation, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Air and ballistic missile defense, 1963 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Boundary conditions of the Sino-Indian conflict, 1963 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Soviet 10th Five-Year Plan, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Patterns of Soviet and East European trade, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Rules of the game, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Pacing industries in the USSR, 1977 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Context of the European arms control and disarmament problem, 1963 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - An atlas of the arms control context, 1964 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Criteria for political acceptability of arms control, 1964 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Significant primary fires from nuclear detonations, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Parametric study of shelter costs, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Soviet reactions to U.S./NATO modernization, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - The U.S.-USSR agreement on cooperation, 1984 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Review of the U.S.-Italy cooperative science program, 1985 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Civil defense communications, 1967 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Postattack recovery of damaged urban areas, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - U.S. passenger transportation, 1967 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Effects of nuclear attack on freight transportation, 1967 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Cost effectiveness of blast shelters, 1968 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Industrial recovery techniques, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Occupational skills and civil defense, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Cost and feasibility of emergency cooperation, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Estimating the magnitude and scope of nuclear attacks, 1968 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - War termination concepts, 1978 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Soviet plan formulation during postattack recovery, 1978 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Soviet construction sector, 1978 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Fallout simulant development, 1965 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Introduction to radiological defense planning, 1965 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Decontamination scheduling procedures, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Exploratory analysis of fire storms, 1965 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - U.S.-USSR economic relations, 1976 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Conflicting views concerning nuclear weapons, 1965 (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
  - Fallout models, 1965 (Box-folder 16 :3)
  - Disintegration rate multipliers, 1965 (Box-folder 16 :4)
  - Air and ballistic missile defense, 1965 (Box-folder 16 :5-6)
  - Mainland China, 1965 (Box-folder 16 :7)
  - Population data base for Western Europe and Japan, 1966 (Box-folder 16 :8)
  - LOTADS (Long Term World Wide Air Defense Study) scenarios, 1966 (Box-folder 16 :9)
  - Coverage diagram program for site evaluation, 1966 (Box-folder 16 :10)
  - Protection against standoff thermal attacks, 1967 (Box-folder 16 :11)
  - Feasibility analysis of over-the-horizon radar systems, 1967 (Box-folder 16 :12)
  - FIPCOM (Fighter Interceptor Program Cost Model), 1969 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Probable trend and magnitude of Soviet expenditures, 1969 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Projections of Communist China GNP, 1969 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Availability and utilization of NFSS (National Fallout Shelter Survey) shelter, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Nth country threat analysis: Asiatic-Pacific area, 1966 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Nth country threat analysis: West Germany, Sweden, Canada, Israel, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Program OPSTRA (Optimal Strategic Allocation), 1968 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Program OPSTRA2, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Strategic choices for the seventies, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Production and allocation of hardware, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Focus on the economics of national security, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Preliminary survey of non-national nuclear threats, 1968 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - EINFALL (European invasion scenario), 1969 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Sensitivity of damage estimates, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Recent USSR arms control and disarmament attitudes, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - National vulnerabilities affecting postattack recovery, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Alternative expectations in SALT, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - U.S. nuclear war deterrence strategy, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Communist takeover strategies, 1977 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Strategic forecast: U.S. Navy in the year 2000, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Computer resources in the AT&T network, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - An AT&T planning guide for NS/EP telecommunciations, 1984 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - City of Detroit attack preparation scenario, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Prediction of congregate-care space, 1977 (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
  - Evaluation of chemical warfare policy alternatives, 1977 (Box-folder 20: 3-4)
  - Civil emergency preparedness, 1978 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Postattack recovery management, 1967 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Incentives and disincentives for nuclear proliferation, 1977 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Institutions involved in the control of proliferation, 1976 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Radiological recovery capabilities, 1968 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - World War II German fire document translations, 1967 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Price indexes for Soviet 18-sector, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Projection of Soviet input-output structure, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Disequilibrium adjustment mechanism, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Deflation of the 18 sector Soviet input-output tables, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Modeling the energy and fuel sectors, 1979 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Disequilibrium adjustment mechanism, 1979 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Analysis of national entity survival, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Parametric study of shelter system costs, 1969 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Countermeasures to possible postattack fiscal problems, 1969 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Evaluation of systems of fire development, 1970 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Civil defense communications, 1968 (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - Industrial model matrix, 1968 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Industrial recovery model constraints, 1968 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Industrial recovery model: bread production network, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Industrial recovery modeling: postattack demands, 1970 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Transportation vulnerability research, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Postwar monetary reform, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Blast-damaged petroleum refineries, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Automated attack-effects information systems, 1970 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Mass contour ratio for fallout, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - Strategic coercion, 1984 (Box-folder 22: 11)
  - Building density and fuel loading, 1969 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Damage inflicted by air raids on the city of Hamburg, 1968 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Hamburg police president's report, 1968 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Experimental investigation of plant uptake contamination factors, 1968 (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - Methodology for area military studies, 1968 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - Armed rebellion and South Africa, 1978 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - U.S. security interests and options in Central Africa, 1977 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Republic of China: strategic forecast, 1985 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Performer organizations and support strategies for fundamental research, 1985 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
  - U.S. strategy in Northeast Asia, 1978 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Effects of mass fires on fallout deposition, 1968 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Soviet concept of national entity survival, 1978 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Decontamination and dose control model system, 1970 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Strategic forecast: U.S. Navy in the year 2000, 1985 (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Politico-military utility of Soviet CD/CEP (Civil Defense/Civil Emergency Preparedness) strategic defense systems, 1979 (Box-folder 24: 8-10)
  - Measurement of Soviet economic processes, 1978 (Box-folder 24: 11)
  - Monitoring nuclear proliferation, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - U.S.-USSR joint working group in chemical catalysis, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Review of U.S.-USSR joint working group in chemical catalysis, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Energy-related research and development in the USSR, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Review of the U.S.-USSR joint working group in electrometallurgy, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Educational systems of the United States and Soviet Union, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Soviet options, 1978 (Box-folder 25: 6-7)
  - DTS (Diplomatic Telecommunication Service) communication processor functional specification, 1985 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Blast/fire interactions, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Nation's transportation systems, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Science and technology as tools for foreign policy, 1980 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - U.S. reconstitution and recovery systems, 1980 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Survival, reconstitution, and recovery, 1980 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - U.S.-Saudi Arabian working group on science and technology, 1978 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Potential vulnerabilities affecting national survival, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Agricultural vulnerability, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Beta dosimetry for fallout hazard evaluation, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Discussion of multi-elelment value systems for urban/industrial areas, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Projecting USSR economic growth, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - NATO force sufficiency, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Strategic air defense wargaming, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Economic impact of rapid expansion of military programs, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Potential GNP (Gross National Product) and government expenditures in the U.S. economy, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Problems in forecasting government expenditures, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Analysis of imbalancing attacks, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Quadratic programming, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Application and improvement of Strell methodology, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - SED (Systems Evaluation Department) strategic systems effectiveness evaluation model, 1971 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Alternative futures in southern Africa, 1979 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Application of the decontamination and dose control model, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Debris distribution as a parameter in blast/fire interaction, 1980 (Box-folder 28: 3)